TherapyDave - Dave Lechnyr, LCSW

Individual Therapy & Couples Counseling in Eugene, Oregon

You are here: [Home](https://therapydave.com/) / Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

_Last updated: August 27, 2024_

This Privacy Policy explains how TherapyDave collects, uses, and discloses information about you when you use this website. Additional definitions, terms, and conditions are stipulated in the [Terms of Service](https://therapydave.com/terms/) and [Disclaimer](https://therapydave.com/disclaimer/) which are hereby expressly incorporated into this document by reference.

HIPAA Notice of Privacy Practices
---------------------------------

If you are considering receiving mental health services as a client, please refer to the [HIPAA Notice of Privacy Practices](https://therapydave.com/notice-of-privacy-practices/) for the specific terms and rights that apply to you.

How We Use Your Information
---------------------------

As you use this website, your personal information may be collected directly from you and automatically from your web browser’s information. Primarily, we use and collect the following information:

* When you sign up for a newsletter, waiting list, or fill out a form, we will store your name and email in order to be able to communicate with you. You can opt out of receiving these by contacting me directly.
* We store any comments or feedback you provide us for the purpose of improving the content of this website.
* We collect analytics with Google Analytics to measure site traffic and usage. You may [opt out of Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
* We use your information to personalize your experience on the website and to provide customer support.

How We Share and Disclose Your Information
------------------------------------------

We may share your information in the following circumstances:

* We may share your information publicly, but only with your permission. For example, with your permission, we may publicly post your photograph, your name, professional titles, and comments on this website.
* We may share your information with companies that provide services for us, such as hosting, marketing and communication services, and payment processing (“Service Providers”). Our policy is to authorize these Service Providers to use your information only as necessary to provide services for us, and require that they not use or disclose your information for any other purpose.
* From time to time, we may be required to provide your information to a third party in order to comply with a subpoena, court order, government investigation, or similar legal process.
* We will not, under any circumstance, sell your personal information.
* We may share aggregated or anonymized information that does not directly identify you.

Data Retention
--------------

We retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collected it, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. When we no longer need to use your information and there is no need for us to keep it to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, we will either remove it from our systems or depersonalize it so that it cannot be linked back to you.

User Rights and Choices
-----------------------

Depending on your location and applicable laws, you may have the following rights regarding your personal information:

* The right to access the personal information we hold about you.
* The right to request correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you.
* The right to request deletion of your personal information.
* The right to object to our processing of your personal information.
* The right to request the restriction of processing of your personal information.
* The right to data portability.

Children’s Privacy
------------------

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. Our website is not intended for children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal data from anyone under the age of 18. If you are under 18, please do not use or provide any information on this website. If we learn that we have collected personal data from a child under 18 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 18, please contact us using the information provided below.

Cookies
-------

A cookie is a small piece of text sent to your web browser by a website you visit. It helps a website to remember information about your visit, like your preferred language and other settings. That can make your next visit easier and the site more useful to you. Cookies play an important role. Without them, using the internet would be much more frustrating.

We use cookies for many purposes. For example, we use them to remember your preferences, to count how many visitors we receive to a page, to help you sign up for our services, or to protect your data. You can control and/or delete cookies as you wish – for details, see [aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Security
--------

This website has reasonable security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control.

Non-US Visitors
---------------

We are committed to complying with this Privacy Policy and the data protection laws that apply to our collection and use of your personal information. We are located in the United States where the laws may be different and, in some cases, less protective than the laws of other countries. By providing us with your information and using this website, you acknowledge that your personal information will be transferred to and processed in the United States and other countries where we and our vendors operate.

You have the right to request access to, correction of, or deletion of your personal information as required by applicable law.

Links to Other Sites
--------------------

This website contains links to other websites. These links are for your convenience, however, we make no representations whatsoever regarding these other websites. You should review the privacy policies of these other websites carefully before providing any information to them. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or procedures or the content of any other site.

Embedded Content from Other Websites
------------------------------------

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if a visitor has visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Contact Information
-------------------

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our data practices, or if you wish to exercise your rights regarding your personal data, please contact us at 2440 Willamette Street, Suite 101-C, Eugene, Oregon, 97405 or by phone at 541-705-4666.

Changes to This Policy
----------------------

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date on this policy. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy whenever you access or otherwise interact with this website so that you can stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

_“Before starting therapy, our relationship felt toxic and hopeless. It seemed like no matter what I tried, nothing changed, and the fate of our marriage was out of my control. Dave saw the love we still had for each other and believed that with the right skills and tools, we could turn things around. During our sessions, I noticed my partner putting in genuine effort, even if consistently applying what we learned outside of therapy was a challenge. I better identified some things I did (and could try to stop doing) that contributed to our couple challenges and learned some strategies of how to create more space for my partner to process and share. As a result, we rediscovered moments of humor and lightness, which helped put our issues into perspective. I realized that my partner deeply wanted to improve our relationship and had a rich inner world of thoughts and feelings, even if expressing them out loud was difficult. This realization alone was a significant step forward.”_

Dave Lechnyr, LCSW  
2440 Willamette Street, Suite 101-C  
Eugene, OR 97405-3170  
Office Hours: Monday – Thursday, 9:00 AM - 6:00 PM  
Phone: 541-705-4666  
  
Proudly serving clients in Eugene, OR, and via telehealth across Oregon and Arizona.  
  
_In crisis? Call the [National Suicide Prevention Lifeline](https://988lifeline.org/) at 1-800-273-TALK (8255). [Additional Mental Health Resources](https://therapydave.com/mental-health-crisis-resources/)._

Now Accepting New Clients in Eugene, OR for Individual and Couples Therapy. Ready to Transform Your Life?

X
